Okay.
So,...ready.
Perfect okay everybody hear me okay perfect looks like it's on
now finally great first off thanks-a-lot for coming everybody really appreciate your time
thanks for attending build and talking to us about data for a little while as you saw
in the keynote we've been spending a lot of time talking about data a
lot about a lot of the new data services that have come into asher over the coming
...over the last couple of years and what I wanted to do in this session...spend a little bit of
time talking about how you can compose and use all of those services together to
call to create what we call a data pipeline what we found was that a
lot of solutions people were trying to build to get the most...of their data
follow the typical pattern we call it a pipeline you might here called the data
...integration project etc but what we're going to look at in this talk is
how you can reach out and collect all of the data that's interesting
to you process it transform it analyze it
...predictions based on it and then get it where it needs to be to drive analyst analytics and
by or drive experiences in your app so that whole flow we talk about is creating
a data pipeline...going to do in this session is talk about how you can use all of these new
analytics services and measure combine them together to create this end-to-end
flow but not only get it created get it done in a way
that it sustainable you can monitor it you can manage it if you check in,
you know, an issue you can quickly that debugged...
and move on from there...to spend a lot of time looking at how we go about creating these types of analytics solutions?
Remember submitting email wasn't expecting that either.
In terms of agenda we'll talk a little bit about what and why what I'm from a what perspective
will be what services can...use what is available today...why might you think
about composing these services in different ways what use cases you can target and,
also spend most of the session today talking through
a specific use case that we see build-out in as you're a fair amount
...customer turn analysis it's as simple as
any ppf subscription service any membership etc that you might be providing to your
customers you want to know how much of...how much of that your customers are using do they like it
they not like it are they likely to use less are they likely to cancel their subscription...you
want to analyze all the data available to you to make these informed choices so we'll look at the customer
...analysis example as just kind of an example use across the
talk will actually build-out that pipeline see how it works et cetera?
And, we'll talk about a few other common use cases but the interesting thing is the
patterns that will look at how to bring the services together can be applied to many more use cases
...this will this use this tangible concrete one kind of govern the talk today and,
lastly I'll talk a little bit about road map and, then open it up for questions at the end.
So, with that before working in the data factory services microsoft I spent time
launching...insight service and these were the types of conversations we've been having with
customers over the last two years and it's really been an interesting set of conversations
...people are saying look there's all kinds of data out there either I'm collecting it I'd like to be collecting it
I'd like to be working with it I'm kind of working with it to answer a bunch of different questions whether
there traditional by questions over more data or different sources of data all the way through
to predictive questions where I'm trying to use data pretty predict what's going to
happen in the future as I mentioned will focus on the kind of predictive customer
...scenario...touch on a few more throughout the talk as well what we're really going to dive
into the customer...scenarios you can see the pieces and parts how to go about building and
analytics pipeline on as your composing all of the various services together.
So, with that that's going to jump into the media the talk and a
...a question we get...a lot is you guys
launched this service called as your data factory why the heck did you call it data factory what...trying to do with
this service and the reason for that was that a lot of the
analytics solutions we saw people building really
follow the typical flow that you'd see in an assembly line in a manufacturing plant
which is you have to collect all of the raw materials you think you may need to your loading dock
you're then going to assemble or create an assembly line that assembly lines
going-to work on those raw materials it's going to have all kinds of fit for purpose machines they
work on that material transform that material combine it and finally you've got some type of
...good and then lastly you want to deliver that
...good ...your consumer...somebody somebody's
...good might be another person's raw material and the process repeats itself so you end up with a
is...manufacturing perspective a pipeline it looks something like this if we were
to overlay more data words on top of this.
We talk about our data sources
are raw materials we need to ingesting collect those data those
date that data from those data sources whether they be on prim data coming from sas apps
data coming from the cloud whether it's a relational database ahead dupes source of file share
etc all of that data we want to be able to work with an address for analytics
purposes we think about ingesting all of that data...and analyze regardless of
shape speed etc we want to be able to work with munged that data
from analysis perspective we might do that simple things like trying
to aggregate and report on data all the way through tomore predictive things
like using data to predict particular outcomes and then lastly you want to able to publisher
data in this particular case or in the sense of this talk publish means taking
that finished good that you've produced from your data pipeline and getting it to where it needs to be for
most efficient consumption what I mean by that is you might be processing data with a do
you want to get it to a relational database or the or data warehouse back on prime to
connect your existing by infrastructure it could mean...no sequel store
or search index with some interesting data that's been generated by your pipelines that applications can
consume it we see all kinds of interesting scenarios for these analytics pipelines
...ingesting transforming data and loading it into places for all kinds of interesting consumption
so if we look at the this predicting customer turn scenario and a little more detail I
...to data sources that will use as are raw materials for the talk one
is a bunch of log files the other one is more structured data and what we'll do is
will build-out analytics pipeline that nears what you might do if you were like
a telescope or a mobile phone carrier where you've got
...people subscribe to your service everybody's got a phone in their pocket so I figured this
would be a good one that everyone can relate to but again the pattern applies very broadly so,
our scenario will be you've got a telescope from a very-high-level the way it works is,
you know, we're...making...phone calls that's being routed...kinds of infrastructure that
infrastructures actually logging everything about our phone calls from the numbers
that we call from the very sim cards due to the length of our calls to the drop of the
call through the quality of the call through to the...that
the particular call took to connect me to you etc all of that data is being...what if we could
...that data to extract insight from it so the first raw material for a pipeline is the
actual log files coming off the cell infrastructure the second raw material that will use for a
pipeline is more structured information every business has data warehouses today
right you seen all of our announcements but whereas every business
has warehouses where you keep that structured information in this particular case for mythical
telescope we're we've got a customer list of your authoritative customer list...very likely
...on prime warehouse somewhere that lists who your customers are
when did they sign up how old they are all the typical stuff you have when, you know,
customer signs up your service at the end of the day with the tokyo's trying
to do is come up with a finish good that looks more like this and being a
data geek I consider this a finished good another data set not being a data geek that's probably
finish good but the idea here is to create a pipeline that can ingest that data
transform that data predict based on that usage data and tell you
which customers which of your customers are more or less likely to churn where
churn here is defined as use less of your service or product or cancel your subscription
with your service or product so we want to be able to do is ingest that data transform that data run
machining learning on that data to come up with this finished good and then do it repeatedly
right because every month role making calls well making decisions and how we feel about,
you know, our cellphone coverage and everything like that so what we'll do is
will create a pipeline that's running all the time and the pipeline is
going-to be working over a month's worth of data at a time so we're going...create a time-based
...where every month will be ingesting this
input data every month will be analyzing and transforming that data to come up with
this data set which is effectively the customers likely to cer next month?
Okay, and,
again,...I consider this a...good but more than likely the actual
...good in something like this will be a report that your marketing team your custer engagement team may want to
pick up and say okay these are the people likely to churn I may want to target them with special offers
...I want to reach out to them and get ahead of customers before they start canceling
...reducing usage points the interesting thing is this pattern is actually something we've
extracted from a set of our customers in production today with data factory in hd inside
and blob store we just generalized it for the...something that
we've got a fair amount of experience with I've just kind of...it to the delco...I thought everybody could relate?
So, with that given this is build that's going to dig in and see how pipeline like this can
be built using the services that are available and...today.
So, first step we need some raw data that's supposed to be a
cellphone tower I apologize for my for art but the raw data here
is cellphone towers all over the place that are collecting these log files typically these files are
called cdr files called detail records they get pushed to all kinds of
file store infrastructure whether that's, you know,
file stores in on prime situation ftp servers
et cetera but they get log then we've got a customer table in on prim data mart data warehouse
et cetera and what we want to be able to do is collect all of that data?
we want to put it into a place that we can run analysis on it at scale regardless of the shape
size or etc of the data so a great way to do that today is to use as your
blob storage just ingest all of the data into
...blob storage built into as your data factory is a globally available data
movement service that knows how to reach backed on prim sources...get data knows how to reach the file
source of file shares and get datamove data among blob stores
so ingesting data can be facilitated by the globally available movement service in data factory
you push that data into blob storage if anybody's not familiar with as your blob storage
its effectively file store in the cloud you can put anything in it it's scale out.
Highly available and its dirt-cheap so you start to be able to take this methodology or mentality
of collect everything is kind of the loading dock if you will of your pipeline or your assembly
line collect everything into blob storage you may have a scenario for that data
out of the gate you may learn about a new scenario for that data down the line collect everything it's
now kind of economically possible to go do that it's really cheap to put things in blob storage once
you've collected stuff your next step is to actually create just like a manufacturing plant create your
assembly line what's going to work on this data and this is where it's pretty fun to be
in data right now obviously...data so I say that but it's really fun time because there's
a lot more tools that we have available then we used to so now it's not just
okay can I represent that data in sql but I can have a bunch of tools that are fit for
purpose depending upon what I want to and with data factory what we can do is compose all of
those fit for purpose tools to work on the data as...as we need so the first thing we're going
to go do is create a pipeline and that pipeline is going to start by using
simply do processing to process these very large collection of
log files if you think about it think of every call anybody's making in the united states for
a particular carrier being able to ingest all of that data and process it monthly
...up with row one row that says might flask go talk to this many minutes...this many drop
calls here this many calls, you know, internationally domestically et cetera that's what
dupe is going to do for us in this particular stage or first stage to
kind of transforming combine the data is going to aggregate all of those call logs to generate
literally one record per customer per month it's going to combine that data with the
on prim reference data which is our customer list so it's not just
...card...long but it's mike flask go of age,
you know, what I know what I put myself in here thirty two talk to this long
...this many drop calls...so now you can get a very personal sense of exactly what
you're customers have been doing in the experience they've had with your service once we've got that data kind...we
...we transformed it with hd insight the next step will be to take that
output data which I've called here the customer called details?
And, push that output data into an as your
machine learning model and we're going to use a machine learning model that's available in the
machine learning gallery what it's going to do is take that data as input one
role per each customer and it's going to look at all that data and compare
it to training data we've used for customers who have cancel their subscriptions in the past and it's going
to predict which customers are likely to churn basically which customers are
more or less likely to cancel their subscription or use less from this particular
telescope and then...that's going to output...data set called customers likely to
churn lastly you may want to move that datasets you may want to take it out a blob
...push back on prim to your data warehouse for reporting you may want to take that data set push it
too, you know, another store for sharing with a partner whatever the
...consumption pattern is for this particular piece of data in this case we're going to do is move the
data to cloud database and measure db going forward the as your
data warehouse service will be a great option it will
be natively supported by data factory and then lastly what-you want-to do is
create a visualization right for me the table and
...is...good for me but foryour marketing team
...customer engagement team they're probably want to report so...here would be some type of report you've,
you've created over top of that data so effectively this is what we want to have
happen we want to work with the actual log files from how people were interacting with their
phones and transform that into report about a...uri
more or less likely to churn based on the experience we've had with the service and we want that to
...every month and we want to unreliable every month and we want it to be able to improve it
...increment on it every month so we want to be able to run this whole thing
is a single pipeline operated as a single...highly available.
I've been using the were data factory...throat
the my description data factory is a purdue preview service we have and measure that
effectively lets you model this entire data flow as what we call a pipeline
in data factory so I'm going to introduce you to three key concepts that's in the data
factory service that allows you to compose these as your services together into these types of
data flows are pipelines the first key concept in data factories called the data set a data set
is just that it's a piece of data you want to work with in your analytics pipeline a
data set could represent a table in a database a piece of structured data a
data set represent a bunch of log files that you have
in blob storage that you want to treated as a single data set it really can represent any piece of data
...a...data set is just a piece of metadata in data factory
in assertion about a piece of data at a particular location next key concept...data factories called
an activity and activity is a processing job it's something that works on the
data either moves data transforms data shapes data doesn't prediction
on data so in our in our scenario today the activities in our
pipelined will be simple dupe activities some
high even pig work followed by the execution of a machine learning model and
measure ml model that's also considered activity and then lastly will move
the data to as your db and that movement step is also considered
an activity in the data factory and the interesting thing again is that
activities are just assertions of work that is going to happen on particular services
the data factory does the job of
orchestrating the work among the services the scheduling the monitoring actually making the pipeline flow.
And, lastly you can organize your activities
into kind of logical sequences we call those things pipelines
...pipeline is just and ordered set of activities it's a logical grouping you think about how you
organize a set of classes into a dl or methods into a class it's the same kind of
thing data factor you organize a set of steps into you know,
whatever granularity you want you could have a pipelined of thirty steps you have a pipeline of
one-step-at-a-time...up to you it's...organizational tool for you to say, you know, what this eighteen
site job followed by this machine learning model invocation followed by this move this particular set of steps
this-is mike calculate customer turn pipeline and that allows me just kind of reason about the things a
little more organized way?
So, with that I think back to the analogy to
the factory floor to the assembly line these are the core steps that you see in a lot of
these solutions collect the data from the data sources that you need
...connect to them ingest them transform and analyze publish the data
...hear me reference that the structure of fairmount throughout the talk today so with
that I hopefully I've set the stage on what
we're trying to do how the various as your services will be used and what role
that play-along are pipeline and now what I'll do is I'll jump out of
slides and get into the as your portal and show you this solution actually running
and as your today and we'll walk...step-by-step and see how it's built?
...so let me flip over here.
The real great okay.
So, we'll start in the as
your portal and if you want to build one of these analytics pipelines the way to start
is by instantiating a data factory data factory think of it just like,
you know, that the manufacturing plant when you create a new data factor it's like having
an empty manufacturing plant there's no assembly lines anywhere it's just like an empty building
so when I go and say I want to create a new data factory your effectively
trading the start of your manufacturing plant a new data factory is
...using any resources it's free to create data factories until you start putting pipelines into
them creating a data factory takes a few seconds it's just a metadata operation.
So, I'm not going to create a new one but instead what I'm going to go do is open one that I've already created that
has the solution running and will look at it so here I've got my
the customer turn the data factory loading up?
On the home blade of data factory you get kind of an added glance view of what's in the
factory we just talked about what datasets are those are all the concrete pieces of data will work
with pipelines again or just sequences of activities the one thing I
didn't mention was linked services links services are very simple
...just the other as your services or other services that
we've link to the data factory that it can...they can communicate with so if I look
at this you can see what I've got here is I've link to the factory a couple of
storage...storage accounts and as your db in as
...machine learning account and then finally a cluster.
And, this is just all of the services that are being composed into my pipelined
by the factory if I wanted to work with some more data maybe I want to work with an oracle database on
prim I can go and add my links service that oracle database maybe
non-credit file share etc so through here I can start to
...more what you'll see is more in-box connectors to various data sources
at each month as we go and there's support in data factory as I mentioned before for
moving data connecting to data sources whether they be on primer cloud the on prime connectivity
...facilitated through something we call
the data management gateway you can set up those gateways right through the cloud portal
as well it gives you a piece of software to install on your side of the firewall and it helps manage communication.
So, let me rollback so now I've got a data factory it's
...to some hd insight clusters and storage accounts sequel db
And, about...pipelines created the best way to work with the data factory if you're coming into one
brand-new I often suggest people to go and click sample pipelines
what this will do is deploy one of our end-to-end samples right into your factories so it
can be up and running and you can see how everything works it's a great way to get started but in this case because
I've already deployed this customer turns scenario I'm going to start with the diagram
view diagram view gives me a complete look at everything that's deployed
in the factory it's an infinite canvas kind of thing so that you can have
is many pipelines as you want in a single factories many datasets as you
author scale limits from that perspective and the idea is that the diagram
view shows you exactly what's deployed and what's healthy and running in terms of pipelines
in your factory and what I'm going to do now is kind of take you from left to right on this
pipeline and show you how it's built this is mimicking what we just looked at in slide's okay?
So, let me zoom in and walk it step-by-step and show you how this is built.
The enough fifth-grade okay that's cool what bigger.
All right so on the far-left we're not actually collecting data live from cellphone towers
as I mentioned we could hook up alive ingestion from file shares if we wanted
there's extensibility points to be able to connect other stores...we've done is we've
just added something on the far-left that is mimicking the generation of
...cellphone log files are called detail records this is actually live in a piece of python code running on
how to cluster so just for fun we use python running on...to generate the data but...typical pipeline
would start right here and it would start with that log data a single
datasets representing all of the log files for particular month
from my delco so maybe all the log files from january...fails from february
The way you do this is you basically
specified just adjacent document adjacent document tells us where the data is
what it structure might be where it's located so what this data actually looks
like in blob store it looks like this is kind of a typical called detail record just a
bunch of semi-structured log files about who called what where how long etc.
And, the...describe that in terms of a pipeline
...a factories to my data set if I double-click
the data set it's going to give me kind of a live view of how healthy that data set is has
been generated etc I can look at the source for the particular data...so we have a
and editor built into the portal as well so you can look at the definition of a data set
and you can edit you can deploy new ones et cetera
but I've copied one out just a...inspecting little more detail.
But, what I'm going to do apps...forgot what I'm going to do is I'm actually going to look at the data
set over here so what's happening in between this piece of data and this piece of data is
one step that is just partitioning the incoming data so if you think of these log files
is coming in all the time being landed in maybe one container and blob store
this one step in this pipeline is just taking the data out of that container taking all
the logs for january putting in a january folder taking...the...february putting
...february folder and its accomplishing that task at scale by running a
hype script on hd insight cluster so if I go down here you can see the activity is
actually a piece of five code it's running on hd insight cluster that's happening at scale
all dig into one of the subsequent hype scripts in a little more detail so I'll just kind of
...over this one for now so at the end of it what
we've got is data that came in one container we partitioned it so it's ready for kind
of longer-term storage and then what I'm going to do is I'm going to dig into this pipeline in these data sets a little more
detail...you can see so partition cdr data
...in blob storage let's look at how you create an actual data set?
Here's the definition of that
...set it's just a simple jason document you can do this programmatic
lee you can do it through the ui like I showed but I wanted to show you is kind of under the covers
possible these things are so to create a data set and added to data factory you create a simple jason
object you name it and it's got three sections structure location availability,
availability is just saying kind of what the frequency is that this data set is being
attended to or updated so you can think of this...time slicing of the data set
so if you imagine that these log files is one big long data set where basically
saying it's sliced monthly so there's the january partition the february partition etc.
We're asserting some structure about this data set
just like in who do you've got a bunch of log file sitting in blob store and
see effectively asserting structure about or schema about what's in that blobs
...what's in those log files and I've actually shorten this just for the
...demo but the idea is that here's the first column and its type here's the second
column and I removed all the other columns just so I don't scroll through the thirty call my
thinker so wide us the schema definition
...lastly this is the kind of meat of the data set definition is location
so data set is just a pointer to a piece of data you saying this data is
in blobs this data is partition by year and month.
...a variable here it's a
common limited file and here's the partitioning scheme and what we're saying is?
This data is partition by your and month and we're using one of the environment
variables we injected into the system called slice start there's also one called slice so,
if you remember I said this particular data set is sliced by time what we mean by
sliced by time is each time there's an activity that runs to
produce this data that activities going to run monthly in this case so slice start would
represent like january first-year slice and represent like january thirtieth so what's happening is
you're just defining the data set and how...partitioned lastly?
We're saying this data set well stored in blob store is stored in this particular
...service so what we do is we have a generic definition about the data and where
...stored in a particular kind in this case a blob storage and then this last
binding to assist to a link service is basically binding it to a particular
blob storage account so at this point all I've done is describe the data that's going to be used by
...subsequent step in the pipeline?
So, if I go back I've got this step that's taking that data set is input it's also
taking another data set called mobile customers as input this data just for the sake of
the demo I...staged into blob store but I could be connecting this up to
and on prime data warehouse and pulling the data from the on prime warehouse using the movement service
provided in the factory but just for simplicity ever move that from the demo for now so I've got a pipeline taking
to datasets and producing one data set on the other side.
What it's going to do is take those log files as I mentioned
that is a bunch of log files for a month that describe all of the
call activity it's going to...down to create,
create one row for every customer and say, you know, okay,
of all the logs are going to find all the records for mike we're going to generate one row for mike and say mike
talked this many minutes in the monthly at this many drop
calls etc we're going to combine it with the customer data so we can basically resolve...card id to
an actual customer name and that's going to be done again by processing step in hd
insight ...as a fantastic tool for running, you know,
data chunking at scale so inside of this pipelines
for edges double-click to have this open up I've got two steps?
One is highly activity followed by
copy activity copy activity I didn't really need to do I just did it to rename the file but the hide
activities the meteor this is something that's going to be spun up to process all of those log
files and aggregate the data basically what I'm doing is I'm preparing the data for input to
a machine learning model if you want to look at the actual hives script that I'm running you
can click pipeline source pipeline source will take you to definition of the
pipeline and subsequently to hives script but if I double click on...here.
And, I click activity script.
You'll see this is just the typical
...hives script that's going to be run to work with that the input
datasets one interesting thing you can see is that hives script is parameterized just like
you parameterized sequel the queries in
app you parameterized the hives scripted take the frequency information like, you know,
in this case we're running monthly so you take the fact that you know,
what the years with the month etc you can download the high file
etc if you're new to hire your new to duped there's a lot of other sessions at the conference that
will talk you through and working through kind of all of the things you can do with the dupe and hd
insight what I wanted to what I want you to take away from this talk is that you can use all of
these services together into a pipelines I'm not a...into the high...too much detail?
Lastly what I want to do is show you this particular pipeline stage
and show you how you go about defining a pipeline in data factory so that you can see
how these data sets are taken as input and
then produces output so again if I double-click the pipeline I can go to
pipeline source that will take you to the web-based editor for the jason document that
represents the pipeline itself I've just copy this out into my sublime text
here too so that we can look at it in that little bit higher.
Vigor...so...drop this come over here and here's the
pipeline definition so this is the definition for the pipeline we were just looking at.
You just again it's a simple jason document is all you're doing is declaring that this
data set is coming as input to this particular...task and it's going to produce this output
so you just have to declare that the system what you do is you give it a name in this case I'm
saying aggregate mobile customer usage some aggregating those logs
...the description I said a start inundate this is just like scheduling
...meeting you say are the recording meeting is going to start january
...in december but it's going to happen monthly so, you know,...btwelve instances of that meeting
...the year and then lastly what you do is there's an array and
there's one object in the array for each step of the pipeline so in this particular case I've
got, you know, ...exploit the whole thing into a few pipelines so let's
to drill nc what one step in a pipeline looks like.
And, again, one step is suggestion object and the first thing I do is I name my step and
...can be aggregate more mobileusage minutes that step is an hd
inside activity it's going to run on the hd insight cluster that's represented by this
...service I'll come back to how you define...service and just a second and what actually is going to run is a
hype script that's located at this location in lobster?
And, this is the blob...located at and these are all the additional
...I want to have automatically bound to my who cluster when this particular
...activity runs there's a lot of configuration you can do here I've showed a little bit of the our
there's a lot more so, you effectively saying run this...script once a month on that
input data and there's a section called extended properties
extended properties are just any variables you want to pass in to your particular hype
scripts execution so each time it executes in this case what's monthly these extend properties
would passed in I...the defined a bunch of them here.
And, you can see what I'm passing in here is your
...day and I'm taking that from the slice start
variable that's kind of an environment variable that's injected by data factory...into the
hives script the fact that hey you're running for the january run of twenty fifteen
right now so I can parameterized my hype...take that is input lastly...specify the to
datasets that will be used as input the reason we have this level of specification is because we can
do interesting things like automatically do precondition checking on those
datasets to cr they available are the meeting certain preconditions so we don't waste time
and resources spinning up hd insight work if the input data just
isn't ready or it's not matching certain preconditions that you specified I'll talk about preconditions a little bit later in the
top and then lastly you say output well this is what the output of the
hives script is actually going to generate it's another data set and blobs.
then we've got a set of policies you...state for that activity I put the simplest policy here which
is to retry policy which means when we spin up that activity this
...script and run it if it fails you want
to retry for-you if so will retry the activity you can do all kinds of things here like
have timed back-office and when you want to retry you can specify what to do
and data arrives later than you expect so let's say you go and
want to run at the end of every month but a certain amount of input data is available you can give us all
kinds of policy that you want to do and how and when we run these activities for you?
And, then I've got another activity along the way as well.
So, that's how you go about specifying a pipeline it's just a jason
the document one object for every activity and you just declare what activities you want to have run
...where you want to run them I'm going to go back to this...service line which was saying run
this hives script on this hd insight cluster.
And, this hd insight clusters defined by...service links service again is just a simple
jason document and what you're seeing here is going to run on this html
...cluster I want the cluster to be hd insight version three-point-one I want
the cluster size
...nodes are two hundred nodes or whatever you choose basically any configuration
you'd want about your eighteenth site service and then lastly?
We specify type anti peer could mean one of two things you can for a lot of
our processing services that we support data factory we have one of to modes the first
mode is you've created the resource up-front...effectively given a
...string to data factory and you said go and use this resource so in this case you would have created
your hd insight...cluster and you give us the connection string over in this particular case
...specified is to use what we call our on-demand html
site feature on-demand means let data factory take care of provisioning
...do cluster for you when it's needed and the provisioning when it's not needed so you can now start to
create these pipelines that use hd insight use virtual machines to run custom code
...and the pipeline will take care of provisioning the infrastructure
two-run that script when needed and the provisioning the infrastructure
when not needed to completely out of the business of any kind of infrastructure management of
...clusters and gm's and whatnot you just give us code you want to run
and where you want to run it and we take care of...it up...it down on your behalf if we need to retry we go get
it back etc so it's a nice feature from that perspective it really gets you kind of
...focus on the various processing steps you want to have happen?
So, let me jump back out into...into our pipeline again so
we've got incoming log data we got customer data we've merged it we produced another
data set which is basically one row for every customer for that month.
And, then lastly I want to show you two more steps
is going to take that data set in blob store that's one row for
...month and I'm going to feed it into a pipeline that has one activity and it
if I double-click you can see down below.
What's actually running inside of that pipeline is an activity but this time it's an activity
that's going to call and as your machine learning model so just like in the prior pipeline we were using the
...service to run some hd insight prepare and aggregate data this time we're going to
call-in as your machine learning model and say hey the output of that
whooped job what's that's ready I want you to feed that into a machine learning model and
that machine learning models going-to-take that output effectively add one column the likelihood of that
customer to churn and the way that all that works.
Is by using...of the machine learning models
...available in the machine learning gallery lone
...for this demonstration called delco customer churn it's
...machine learning model that looks like this you probably saw it machine learning introduced by joseph
in the...earlier today this is a model that's been built to
and built-in trained based on
...togo usage logs so the idea is that you can feed logs
to this model and it will with pretty good accuracy determine is this customer likely
to cancel their subscription or use less based on the training data that was fed
...this model the training data is
effectively data of logs of customers that actually cancel their...less so
use that pattern that recognition to figure out what which customers are likely to
churn so I'm certainly not a data scientist...I'm not going to walk through what all
the steps are within this model but the idea is that?
As a developer what you can do is you can work with the various models that are available
compose them into your data factory pipelines and use them just as
a web service so the way we actually built this is we had one of the data
scientists go create this model for us and he tuned it and,
... I he tells me it's very accurate and then he goes
any prepares this model as a web services joseph showed in the keynote and then as
a developer I can just use this by calling the web service and the way it works is
that using a batch scoring approach which what that means from the machine learning perspective
is that I call the web service and I tell the web service...in blob storage the
input data is so I don't shuffle the data to the web service over http or anything like that
simply call the web service and say please score all the data in this
...in this file in blob storage and put the output over here so that
capability is natively built into...once you once you create a web service
based on your model so as a developer I didn't need to know all of the to class
...support the imagers that are going on here instead I needed to know
how to call that machine learning model and the schema of the input data that was required so from
a data factory perspective I just added in this step to call that
model and I tool that take the data from this blob store write your output to this blob store.
And, then lastly.
I created a step that said copy the data from
sorry about that copy the data from blob storage to
sequel db okay so you can see on this side the
...blob store on this side it's the same data that I moving over to sequel
db now that I've created that interesting results...that is telling me the customers that are likely to
churn is one thing I want to show you about that copy activity and then we'll look at the actual data this
copy activity interesting is what's actually performing the copy under the covers
what inside of the data factory service we have a globally available copy service that
basically moves data among as your stores from on prime to asher et cetera so,
that all you need to do to specify data movement is to
common say well it's this data as input and I want this thing is output maybe in this case from
blob the sequel and you don't worry about spinning up
gm's when the copy will happen retrying the copy the system just takes care of it for
you so the copy in this case is a...saying this data set is input this
...output go and if you want to do some type of projection during the
copy like hayley take these three columns from the
input set and put them over here you can you can specify that projection just in the
jason document in this case I'm just doing a straight copy so I'm saying the sources blob
storage skip the first-line because I've got headers in the first-line and the destination is
as your sequel and actually call this stored product on the way integer sequels I want
that to be called instead of directly writing in and here's the input and output data set and I just put that into my
pipeline the copy happens for me so it's a nice facility that's offered insider data factory.
So, now if this thing all runs end-to-end nicely like it's
supposed to each month what I should be doing is going from the data that looks
like that and that structure customer data to some structured piece
of data that includes the likelihood ofchurn for each customer so
if you recall here are output is a data set in sql if I connect
to that database and run a query against that table that's being copied to
by the pipeline and I select out a few the columns and the last column
selecting out is scored probability this is the...that's added by the machine learning model what
effectively done is I've aggregated all that log data
...predicted using the ml model and this is the output
and,... to data people this is a...good...will look at how to get reports
and second so what you've got here is this data was coming from that structured data
the customer list this data is a bunch of aggregation that came from the
logs themselves and this particular data is data that came from the machine
learning model itself so effectively what it's saying is customer seven two nine six three of age
seventy-nine is a female she had a six percent drop call rate that month
...one percent failure rate that...talked eighty-one minutes and she has a ninety percent likelihood of
churning and it's not just these factors that went into the model but I've just select about these
three so that you can kinda see the structured results that came out the other side into the db so
what I want you to take away from one of these pipelines is that the idea is being able to
work with and collect all of the interesting data use the appropriate as your service of
choice to operate in transform on that data whether it's
...dupe custom code on ibm as
...ml etc and then push that data to the store or place
...can most easily be consumed...have that run consistently you know,
our in our out every month every week whatever the cycle is that makes sense for you in this case we've
got this thing running monthly and then lastly want obviously once you've got something into a nice structured
form like this you can go in create snazzy looking reports that.
Represents all that data so we quickly when created one that was a our
...visualization our buys one of our new analysis tools and all
I've done is graft that customer turn data so I can drill in is just talking to the
database that that's being updated by the pipeline and I can say good most of my customers
in blue here aren't likely to churn but the ones in purple are likely to churn let's kind of
drilling and figure out why that might be well it turns out there's nothing to do with the type of job they have
actually has nothing to do type of education they have but people in,
you know,...this particular state seem to be showing
more likelihood then this other states let's start drilling in there and seeing what was happening maybe in the infrastructure
in that place you can start to drill in get more insight into what was happening what was causing these people
start...and you can visualize that data in interesting ways with rbi but from a analytics
perspective want to take away is that you can build these pipelines you can operate
them you can get kind of a complete end-to-end view of the data and then
you...them...regular basis...jump back into.
...slides here.
I'll skip this one will quickly and give you a quick summary of
data factory what it's a service to let-you orchestrate schedule and monitorexisting
as your services so you can compose them together to create pipelines like this it
does automatic infrastructure management I showed it for...quickly you'll see it coming for custom code on
...m it has a movement service built into it
...easily facilitate movement among your various stores both on
...will be adding ever new connectors each month we just finished adding the oracle connector and the on
profile share connector and, then lastly provides you a single pane of glass one place to log
into to see how your data is moving how it's being transformed how things are going and I'll
show you an example of that in a little larger data factory in just a second.
In terms of a few other scenarios that we've been
seeing people wanting to build-out these types of analytics pipelines are things from
generating product recommendations for websites if you were in one of the earlier modern data
talks you saw how big data was being used to augment the search results...as
...search index typically you'd be running that on a schedule every day all the time to
be...the data for those search results another class of usage that we see a
lot is what we call operational excellence scenarios where people are building telemetry
systems where if you think about any kind of sas application or, you know,
device that you might be monitoring devices are constantly
emitting all kinds of data and information that you need to aggregate
predict on etc to determine what's availability of your services whatever latency
...customers doing with it etc so we see a lot of us
asks the application builders through to industrial automation
companies using data factory and lobster and html.
To ingest all of the telemetry information from their website
through to their oil and gas pipeline and then creating just series of
...pipelines to work on that data transform that data give you different views
over it going to get more insight out of out of the systems...what I want to do is login
...other data factory that represents one of these telemetry systems to give you
an idea of the types of things you can doas these as the system start to grow up.
Great we're back so let me jump out of this customer
turn demonstration and jump into a different one I'm going to call the data factory data lake.
You can use one's a little bigger it's got a hundred-fifty for datasets and it let's go to the diagram.
What this is actually this is the data factory we use to
run data factory so worldwide this data factory services up
...collecting logs all the time about what pipelines were running
were orchestrating what's up what's down and we use
a data factory to ingest all kinds of telemetry from commerce telemetry through
...usage telemetry to our live site telemetry and we munch all that together to figure out what
our users are doing what they're experiences like what's working well what's not working
well etc effectively how we run and operate data
...service itself a lot of other as your services and microsoft services do the same and,
what I want to show you?
In this factory is how these things kinda grow up over...
this particular factories actually not that old there's a lot of stuff going on here some people say
man that looks ugly...did you laid out like that like these lines go over well turns out this is the way
our telemetry team likes it laid out it makes sense to...we're trying to do with data factory is give you
a effectively alive visio canvas or live diagram of exactly
what's deployed how things relate to each other and let you organize...
collapse it expand it however you see fit so garner the days when you decide
to...design...data integration project gets written on the whiteboard or
put...visio document of some kind and that's the last time you ever see a pictorial representation that's up
to date with data factory what we're trying to do is say you've got a live diagram of all of
your data integration overlaid with health information and usage information that you can log
into you can customize it's...to however makes sense for you it's yours but it's up
to date it's live it's an accurate representation of the system.
If I drill in you can see well I've got some
stuff that's read something in our telemetry system's not working well you can maybe ask me wired which is
...read but that's a conversation for another day and,
I can start now to kind of added glance drill in and say hey through this fairly complex network of
pipelines what's going on so if I drill in to one of these.
One of these ...the datasets here.
And, you can see this particular data set it really hasn't had one of
its time slices be for fielding quite some time so you ends kind of
look at what's going on here so by drill into one of these.
You can see we've had a bunch of retry...the systems done for me automatically every one of those
of failed and their statuses fail validation and...message says a
blob at this particular location does not exist that's pretty small I dunno...everybody can see it as a
blob at this very particular location doesn't exist this is just showing you some of
the simple validation that are available data factory where you can say look I need
this input data I'm going to ingested into my pipeline if it's not there or
...smaller than a particular size or hasn't been updated since a certain date then it's not
needs useful to me so don't even start running the pipeline just fail validation
up-front something's wrong so in this particular case we're expecting a partner team to be putting a file
there for us to consume that file hasn't been put there for a while so the pipeline is
not starting it's failing validation in alerts get sent to us automatically that particular stage in my pipeline
is failed once that stage gets fulfilled in the condition gets met data factory has a bunch of features for
...can come in and say okay rerun that pipeline as if it was,
you know, three days ago when it started failing and then cascade that all the way down so
anything else that's waiting on that gets kicked off as needed when needed et cetera so,
there's a lot of nice features built-in factory so that you can kind of manage a larger data
...for a larger telemetry system like this so that was just a quick look at
of what a larger system starts to grow up into and again this
...a system that you can customize so if I take a lock off I can start to
drag things around and...it my own multiple people can at the surface however
they see fit I will undo that because people get mad at me when I change their work?
There's a question that said I print that today we don't have a feature in-box that we're going to
printed layout nicely ...one we've heard a lot those so we'll look at doing an
...for print and in some.
So, that showed you a couple other factories really quickly.
Let me now jump back to slide's...got a couple minutes left.
Need to be...can't see the time thing.
Clearly wasn't...stage made for me all right so in terms of
road map I showed you a little bit about what data...can be that can do
for-you today how to create pipelines things that you'll see coming in this area in the
future is that you get a lot more authoring support you'll
see visual studio integration you'll see pipeline templates you can create pipelines like the
one I showed from a template and then just fill in the missing pieces you'll see a
lot more connectors coming to data factory there's some coming in the coming weeks
...be adding them weekly from here out there's connectors coming
...document to be search sequel...data lake all the stuff that you've heard about you can efficiently
move data among these sources and create pipelines that...them
...be additional activities so that you can execute stored...dw
through a bunch of interesting stuff coming in that space there's some work will do to make it easier to
handle reference data like that customer list we were looking at there's a bunch that's coming in
terms of improving and adding to that monitoring view so you can really have a single pane
of glass to see how your data is moving how it's being transformed whether it's healthy or not.
And, then lastly what I showed you today with how to create a pipeline
that...a lot of processing services in manager a lot of the storage systems and measure but
we're opening up the entire system of data factory so that if you want to go and
...in a new processing
system what I mean by processing system is something like hd inside or something like as your
...you can go add your own you can go adds support for your own so we're working with
partners right now that have spark as a service and other processing platforms
and they're adding support for those platforms into factory so you can create pipelines that
...all kinds of different systems to
basically use the right tool for the job for very for your various tasks and easily
stitched together or compose these various systems into a pipeline so the be and extensibility
sdk that will release its already available in limited preview right now as I mentioned or working
at various partners that both have systems on prime and in the cloud so you'll be able
to truly create hybrid pipelines and managing monitor them from one place and,...
that's an exciting new area that's coming in data factor you just kind of what your appetite
...if you're interested in learning more about that feel free to ping me and then lastly
geo location today you can create...data factory in one of the...geo location...of the as
your regions from that region you can orchestrate things across all of the rest so you can create
a pipeline that works across all the regions today you'll see data factory the orchestrate
a of data factory be available other regions in the coming months as well.
With that I thought I provide a few resources is one of the first
sessions we've done on data factory and how it can combine so we tried to do is
provide a lot of resources if you're interested to dig in and learn more hopefully it
kind of whet your appetite for things you can do there's a lot of good documentation windows
...dot com we've got to get hub repo just for data factory samples we
are all years on what you'd like to see for samples we've uploaded some we change them all the time we'll
probably put this customer churn example up there as well in the coming week there's a place to ask questions
...a place to ask for new features there's a lot of financial services companies you can
imagine do all kinds of interesting things with data we've taken the best of what we've learned from them so far with
...that in architectural pattern we call a blueprint that's going to be
published later this week so-if you want-to see what some of our customers like millman is
doing in terms of actuarial automation using data factory and html...
store you'll be able to...the best practices we've extracted from that there's a set of other case studies available here
on what customers are doing to create analytics pipelines using as your today with...you know,
a lot more to come one thing all note is that data factors currently in preview we have a number of
customers running and production already it's a service we've been running inside of microsoft for a while
now running production loads for some of our biggest services whether it's xbox microsoft
studios due to our microsoft into the services all of them run in
our powered by data factory today so we're free pretty confident about kind of how battle hardened
it's become inside the company now that we've started to bring it outside?
With that I want to thank everybody for your time I really appreciate it I appreciate
...talk to-you about data
...be available at the booth for the next couple of hours after the session but I think we have with a couple of
minutes so I'm happy to take any questions that people have it'll stick around for a few minutes after that thank you very much
...it thanks.